Christine Schatz

Junior Software Developer

Phone 323-828-8487EastonE-mail cmschatz@gmail.comPA

WWW www.christineschatz.com

LinkedIn www.linkedin.com/in/christineschatz

I'm inspired by crafting creative solutions to problems, whether it's building the right architecture for data on the backend or creating a beautiful user experience on the front end. I enjoy working with good people who love to share ideas and make a difference.

Experience

PetFlow, New York, NY

- Implemented front end features
- Used PHP (Laravel) on the back end
- Wrote unit tests
- Refactored parts of a large codebase

10-2015 - 12-2015

Junior Developer (contract)

ValuePenguin, New York, NY

- Built interactive tools such as a financial calculator using React
- Used Scala and PHP on the backend
- Developed in Docker containers

07-2013 - 06-2015

Web Editor & Coordinator

Lafayette College, Entrepreneurship Program, Easton, PA

- Developed the footprints for an entrepreneurship program
- Customized departmental website using JavaScript and HTML

Education

Northampton Community College, A.S. Computer Science

2015 Dev Bootcamp, Web Development

2008 University of California, San Diego, B.A. Visual Arts, Media

Languages

JavaScript (React, Riot, jQuery)

Ruby (Rails)

PHP (Laravel)

Scala

Additional Activities

08-2010 - present Founder and owner of The Loop

I run an award-winning music blog

09-2015 Coders > Cancer Hackathon

Participated in a hackathon to benefit breast cancer. I led a team that built an app called Ladybug.

Built with: Ruby on Rails